(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T18:00:30.954469",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
なくしてしまった夜のことは
About the nights I've lost...
悲しい話じゃない 寂しくなるけどいいんだ
It's not a sad story, though it makes me lonely, it's fine.
明かりを ずっと消したまままで
With the lights kept off all along,
眠れない日は
On nights I can't sleep,
借りたままだったレコードに
On the record I borrowed,
針を落としたら 情けないステップで踊らせる！
If I drop the needle, I'll dance with these pathetic steps!
ずっとずっと 待ち焦がれていた
All along, all along, I'd been longing for
明け方の陽も 消えない今日も
The dawn's light and a day that won't fade.
今夜 今日のこの夜に
Tonight, even in tonight's darkness,
沈んでしまっても きっと 街の影を
Even if I sink into it, I'm sure the city's shadows
照らす明かりが 昨日と違って
Illuminated by lights, different from yesterday,
柔らかく見えたから
Seemed so gentle to me,
目を 閉じるよ。
So I'll close my eyes.
眠りにつくよ。
Head to sleep.
君の夜をくれ。
Give me your night.
ずっとずっと 聞きたかった
All along, all along, I've wanted to hear
明け方の陽に 笑い合う声を！
The sound of laughter in the dawn's light!
今夜 今日のこの夜も
Tonight, even tonight's night
終わってしまうけど
Will come to an end, but—
明かりは小さく つけたままで
I'll leave the lights on low,
目を伏せて
Cast my eyes down,
冷めたままの珈琲を
Pouring the still-cold coffee
喉に流して
Down my throat.
借りたままだったレコードに 涙がこぼれたら
If my tears fall on that borrowed record,
情けない僕を また 笑ってくれて
Go ahead and laugh at my pathetic self again.
きっと 街の影を
I'm sure the city's shadows
照らす明かりが 昨日と違って
Illuminated by lights, different from yesterday,
柔らかく見えたから
Seemed so gentle to me,
君の夜をくれ。
Give me your night.
冷めたままの珈琲を 喉に流して
Pouring cold coffee down my throat...
借りたままであったレコードに 涙がこぼれたら
If tears spill onto the record I borrowed,
情けない僕を また笑ってくれ
laugh at pathetic old me once again.
きっと 街の灯りを 照らす灯りが 昨日を閉じて
Surely the lights illuminating the city streets close yesterday away,
柔和く見えたから 温かさに 今日は眠れる
and looking so soft, in that warmth I can sleep today.
優しい夜をくれ
Give me a gentle night.
風はもう冷たいけれど
The wind is already cold,
懐かしい空の匂이가したんだ
but it carried the scent of a nostalgic sky.
ホームから踏み出せる
Step by step from the platform,
この場所で君を探してる
I'm searching for you in this place.
季節外れのサーフボードに あの夏はきっと生きてる
On an out-of-season surfboard, that summer definitely lives on.
太陽はずっとおぼえていたはずさ
The sun must have remembered it all along—
ねえ 聞こえている？
Hey, can you hear me?
涙は見せないって
"I won't show any tears,"
君はそう言って 僕たちは二人手を振った
you said, and the two of us waved goodbye.
さようならは言わない だから手を振った
We wouldn't say farewell, so we waved our hands instead.
夕焼けに消えた 痛いめまいよ
Oh, painful dizziness that faded into the sunset!
錆びたギターを抱えるたびに あの歌が胸の奥を掴むけど
Every time I hold a rusted guitar, that song grips deep inside my chest,
今もまだ冴えない日々 この場所で僕は過ごしてる
but even now, in these dull days, I spend my time in this place.
だけど思うんだ 誰かのために きっと僕らは生きてる
Yet I think, surely we live on for someone's sake.
太陽がきっと教えてくれたんだ
The sun must have taught me that—
ねえ 聞こえている？
Hey, can you hear me?
涙は見せないって 君はそう言って 僕たちは二人手を振った
"I won't show any tears," you said, and the two of us waved goodbye.
さようならは言わない だから手を振った 夕焼けに消えた 痛いめまいよ
We wouldn't say farewell, so we waved our hands instead, oh painful dizziness that faded into the sunset!
あれからの僕は 変わりはしない
Ever since then, I haven't changed much,
だけど 本当に少し 自信があるんだ
but I actually feel a tiny bit more confident now.
誰よりも強く生きていかなくちゃ
I have to live stronger than anyone else.
さようならは言わない だって目を閉じて すぐに会える
I won't say farewell, because if I close my eyes, I can meet you right away.
考えてたことが言葉に出ない
The thoughts I had won't come out in words
行き場を失った後悔と焦りが泥のように
Lost regrets and impatience, like mud...
ただ真っすぐに見ていたいだけなのに
Even though I just wanted to look straight ahead
今日も見切りをつけた 夜を真っ暗にしてしまった
Today too, I gave up and left the night pitch black
明かりを灯し続けている
Keeping the lights lit
この部屋が宇宙の大聖堂だ
This room is the universe's cathedral
私から出たSOSだけ届いてないよな
Only the SOS from me hasn't reached you, huh
涙をずっとしまってる どんな傷跡があるか
I've always kept my tears hidden, wondering what scars remain
見てたくて完成するまで 悲しみをこぼしている
Wanting to see until it's complete, spilling my sadness
不安を感じていたのかが 体のどこか知らないけど
I don't know where in my body I felt the anxiety
こんな場所でまで縛り続けていく 理由を見つけてんだ
Finding a reason to keep binding myself even in a place like this
果てしない 呼吸も鼓動も
Endless breathing and heartbeat too
不安定な形も 完璧に見える時も
Unstable shapes, and times when they look perfect
真っ直ぐ後ろばっかり 躓くのは怖い
It's scary to keep stumbling looking straight back
この場所だけは 私のこと知ってるんだ
Only this place knows who I am
手を引いて 向こう場所をしめすのだ
Pulling my hand, showing the place beyond
そう思えば 強く輝けるから
If I think that way, I can shine brightly
届いてほしいのは SOSじゃなくて
What I want to reach you is not an SOS
優しい言葉
But gentle words
涙をずっとしまっても 笑顔のままで出口が縦で
Even if I keep my tears hidden, smiling with vertical exits...
駆け抜け 君の元まで さあ一体んでたどり着くよ
Running through, right to your side, stepping forward to arrive
孤独を感じていたのかが 体のどこか知らないけど
I don't know where in my body I felt the loneliness
本の少しでも 君に近づきたい
Even just a little bit, I want to get closer to you
何かが変わればいい
Hoping something would change
私から出た やさしい言葉だけ 君に届いてほしい
I want only gentle words from me to reach you
小さな宇宙に 生まれただけ
Just born into a small universe
遠い場所から 君を見つけただけ
Just finding you from a distant place
涙をずっとしまってる どんな傷跡になるか
I've always kept my tears hidden, wondering what scars they'll become
知りたくて完成するまで さよならはこぼしている
Wanting to know until it's complete, spilling our farewells
不安を感じていたのかが 体のどこか知らないまま
Not knowing where in my body I felt the anxiety
こんな場所でまだ縛り続けていく 理由を見つけたんだ
I found a reason to keep binding myself in a place like this
ああ…
Ah...
もうすぐ時計は6時
It's almost six o'clock
もうそこに一番星
The first star is right there
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
Stepping on shadows, on the way home blending into the night
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search
一つしかない星
There's only one star
何億光年 離れたところから あんなに輝く
Shining so brightly from millions of light-years away
いいな 君は みんなから愛されて
How nice, you are loved by everyone
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
"No, I've always been all alone"
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If we could gather together and become a constellation...
もうすぐ時計は6時
It'll soon be six o'clock,
もうそこに一番星
And the first star is already there.
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる帰り道
Stepping on shadows, wanting to melt into the night on my way home.
どんなに探してみても
No matter how hard I search,
一つしかない星
There's only one star.
何億光年 離れたところから あんなに輝く
Shining so brightly from hundreds of millions of light-years away.
いいな 君は みんなから愛されて
How nice, you are loved by everyone,
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
"No, I'm all alone by myself."
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we gathered together and became a constellation,
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
On a starry night, a fleeting wish
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えているシグナル
Twinkling, wavering, a trembling signal
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we gathered together and became a constellation,
空見上げて 指をさされるような
Looking up at the sky, like being pointed at
つないだ線 解かないで
The connected lines, don't untie them.
もうすぐ時計は8時
It'll soon be eight o'clock,
夜空に満天の星
Countless stars fill the night sky.
何億光年 離れたところには もうないかもしれない
Hundreds of millions of light-years away, it might not even be there anymore.
月が綺麗で 泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so beautiful, I feel like crying
いつかの日 か別れが来るから
Because a farewell will come someday.
流星みたい 流れるひとりごと
Like a shooting star, a flowing monologue
消えていく残像は 夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism.
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we gathered together and became a constellation,
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If a heartfelt wish reaches someone,
変わるかな 夜のふちを なぞるような
Will it change? Like tracing the edge of the night,
こんな僕でも
Even a person like me...
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we gathered together and became a constellation,
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If a heartfelt wish reaches someone,
変われるかな 夜のふちを なぞるような
Will I change? Like tracing the edge of the night,
こんな僕でも
Even a person like me...
はるかかなた 僕は出会ってしまった
Far away, I happened to meet you.
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
Because of karma, we meet over and over again.
雲のすきまで
Through the gaps in the clouds...
君と集まって星座になれたら
If we gathered together and became a constellation,
夜ひろげて 描こうよ空ごと
Spread the night sky, let's paint the whole sky
暗闇を照らすような 満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon illuminating the darkness,
だから集まって星座になりたい
That's why I want to gather and become a constellation.
いろどりどりの光 放ような
Releasing colorful lights like...
つないだ線 解かないよ
The connected lines, I won't untie them.
君がどんなにまぶしくても
No matter how dazzling you are.
皆さん こんにちはー
Hello everyone!
はい、えーいつもの挨拶いきたいと思います。
Right, um, let's do the usual greeting.
星街のことから現れた星の原石、アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
I'm Hoshimachi Suisei, an idol VTuber, a diamond in the rough from the comet!
すいちゃんだよー！
It's Suichan!
今日もかわいい！ありがとうございます！
You're cute today too! Thank you very much!
皆さんコメントしっかりと見届けております。
I am watching everyone's comments closely.
ありがとうございます！今日もかわいい、ありがとうございます！
Thank you! "You're cute today too", thank you!
えー、本日、私誕生日なんです！わー！
Um, today is my birthday! Yay!
18歳になりましたー！
I turned 18!
去年も18歳だった、一昨年も18歳だった。
I was 18 last year, 18 the year before last too.
えー、そして、活動5周年になります。
And, it marks my 5th anniversary of activities.
わー、5周年長かったような、短かったような、あれどっちも後ろだ
Wow, 5th anniversary, feels like it was long, or short, wait, both are behind me—
はい、ということでこちら星街すいせい5周年ライブでたくさんツイートしてくださいね！よろしくお願いします！
So, please tweet a lot with the Hoshimachi Suisei 5th Anniversary Live hashtag! Thank you!
この後もたくさん盛り上がる曲用意してるので、もっともっと盛り上がっていきましょう！
We have lots of exciting songs prepared for after this, so let's get even more hyped up!
それでは次の曲いくぞー！
Now then, next song, let's go!
鳴り響く怪奇件に付き合わされ
Dealing with a noisy bizarre case,
14ポンド笑うベット
Laughing 14 pounds, a bed
ふふ、臨界実験に付き合う朝
Fufu, the morning of a critical experiment,
14ポンドを嘲るベッド
mocking 14 pounds on the bed.
「如何しようもないけど」
"There's nothing we can do about it, but"
ああ、面倒くさかったから切り捨てた
Ah, it was such a hassle, so I cut it loose,
4Uサイズを攫う烙印
a brand snatching up that 4U size.
「申し訳ないけど」
"I'm so sorry, but"
擦れ違うモノに無為に期待を背負わせている
forcing futile expectations onto passing things.
夜更かしはイドの暴走
Late night rampages of the id,
目に焼き付いた青の感光
blue light burned into my eyes,
モラトリアム的人生
a moratorium-like life,
最大公約数緩衝材
the greatest common divisor cushion.
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる 起きてまた寝て人でない？
Eat, sleep immediately, and turn ugly; wake up, sleep again, not even human?
「失敗！」
"Fail!"
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー
Maximizer, maximizer,
急転 相まって壊したってフェド狂うなんてこと、死んでしまう
turning fast and breaking together as if going mad, till I die!
だがツマミは回る鴇字絡みMATE！
Yet the knob spins, tangled in Ibis MATE!
サンク コスター サンク コステス！
Sunk coster, sunk costest!
同位体 終いには取り戻したいって
Wanting to take back the isotope in the end,
「間隙地獄へ堕ちる！堕ちる！」
"Falling, falling into the abyss of hell!"
but a 眩み unbalance 乖離 faraway
but a dazzle, unbalance, alienation, faraway.
ふふ、生還実験に繰り出すアラーム
Fufu, the alarm heading out for survival tests,
旧四ロンドを微微笑らす劣等
an inferiority smiling at the old four rondo.
「如何しようもないから」
"Since there's nothing we can do,"
気 が狂うヒトの真似をしているキミへ
to you, mimicking a lunatic losing their mind.
「簡単な言葉、信じたいなら足りないよ」
"If you want to believe simple words, it's not enough."
「申し訳ないなら既に合う音に不意に解は求めないよ」
"If you're truly sorry, don't suddenly seek answers in matching sounds."
後悔はエゴの暴走
Regret is the rampage of ego,
手に焼き付いた青の残像
blue afterimages branded in my hands,
モラトリアム的人間
a moratorium-like human,
最小公倍数断頭台
the least common multiple guillotine.
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる 起きてまた寝て人でない？
Eat, sleep immediately, and turn ugly; wake up, sleep again, not even human?
「参っちまうな、マキシマイザー」
"How vexing, maximizer."
救世愛待って焦がしたってフェド狂うなんてこと、痛い聞いてしまう
Waiting for savior love and burning up, asking if it goes mad, it hurts to hear.
だが恨み逆巻く惨劇またgate
Yet hatred surges, a tragedy once more at the gate.
「失敗！」
"Fail!"
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー
Maximizer, maximizer,
急転 相まって壊したってフェド狂うなんてこと、死んでしまう
turning fast and breaking together as if going mad, till I die!
だがツマミは回る鴇字絡みMATE！
Yet the knob spins, tangled in Ibis MATE!
サンク コスター サンク コステス！
Sunk coster, sunk costest!
同位体 終いには取り戻したいって
Wanting to take back the isotope in the end,
「間隙地獄へ堕ちる！堕ちる！」
"Falling, falling into the abyss of hell!"
but a 眩み unbalance 乖離 faraway
but a dazzle, unbalance, alienation, faraway.
マキシマイザー マキシマイザー
Maximizer, maximizer...
触れてみたい秘密と
Secrets we want to try touching,
壊してみたい夜の中で
inside the night we want to ruin.
間違いだらけの遊びしようよ
Let's play a game full of mistakes.
別に意味とかないけれどさ
There's no particular meaning, but
眠い目を擦る
I rub my sleepy eyes.
あれ？待ち合わせは何時？
Huh? What time is our meeting?
「君はまだ履き違えている」
"You're still misunderstanding your role,"
「また間違えている」
"you've got it wrong again."
それで？貴方はいったい誰なの
And so? Exactly who are you?
こうして居たって痛いのはお互い様
Sticking around like this hurts us both.
目が合う度に名を呼ばないで
Don't call my name every time our eyes meet.
どうやったって見たいの？隠さないから
How badly do you want to see? I won't hide it.
私のフリした私で良ければどうぞ
If my pretend self is fine with you, go ahead.
塞ぐ目に落ちる景色のように
Like scenery falling into my blocked eyes,
霞む私誰のもんでもないの
the hazy me doesn't belong to anyone.
buy me
so feeling
からかわないで
please don't kid around.
私だけに見せて
Show it only to me,
歪な夜をどうぞ
the twisted night, please.
嗚呼もうほんとうざったいやいやいやいやいやー
Ah, it's really so annoying, no, no, no, no!
何処かの誰かと赤の信号渡るよいでしょ？
Crossing at a red light with someone somewhere, that's fine, right?
ダメダメダメってわかるでしょ？
You know it's no good, right?
青に染まってたんじゃつまんないいやいやいやいやー
Being dyed in green light is so boring, no, no, no!
ドクドク流れるテロップ 交わる言葉に絡めるシロップ
Teletype flowing steadily, syrup entangling our exchanged words.
早くドキドキさせてよほら
Hurry up and make my heart race, hey.
腐敗する誰かと私のエゴ
Someone rotting away and my ego,
たまらないわ
it's unbearable.
いつものように騙し騙され重なる狂気
Madness piling up, deceiving and being deceived like always.
揺れるように無情にあとはただ落ちるだけ
Swaying heartlessly, after that, just falling down.
触れてみたい秘密と
Secrets we want to try touching,
壊してみたい夜の中で
inside the night we want to ruin.
間違いを繰り返して
Repeating mistakes,
触れてみたい秘密を
the secrets we want to try touching,
壊して知る夜の味を
the taste of the ruined night we know.
戻れないはじめましてをどうぞ
Here is our point of no return, nice to meet you.
触れてみたい秘密と
With the secrets we want to try touching
壊してみたい夜の中で
In this night we want to try ruining
間違いだらけの遊び
Let's play a mistake-riddled
しようよ
game
別に意味とかないけどさ
There's no particular meaning to this, but
眠い目を擦る
I rub my sleepy eyes
あれ？ 待ち合わせは何時？
Huh? What time's our appointment?
「君はまだ履き違えている」
"You're still playing the wrong role"
「また間違えている」
"You got it wrong again"
それで？貴方は誰なのかな
And so? Who are you?
こうして居たいが痛いのはお互い様
Wanting to stay like this and hurting is mutual
目が合う度に名前を呼ばないで
Don't call my name every time we meet eyes
どうやったって見たいの？隠さないから
How do you want to see me? I won't hide, so
私のフリした私で良ければどうぞ
If you're fine with my pretense, here you go
それでは、次の曲いきますよ！
Now then, let's move on to the next song!
本日のゲスト、可不！
Today's guest, KAF!
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
The tempo is high-voltage, totally electrified!
あなたにも忘れたいことかないことあるのかしら
I wonder if there's anything you want to forget
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのはドラマが足りていないからよ
Shedding tears at an unknown movie due to lacking drama
そんな愚にも付かないことくだらないこと
Thinking only about such foolish
考えてばかりね
and pointless things
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も誰かのものになるのでしょう
When the rain stops, love and that profile will belong to someone else
嘘ばっかりのファンタジーも全部今夜のためよ
All these fake fantasies are just for tonight
なのに一体全体如何して何故？
But why on earth, how, and why?
不安定なカンテラ何処まで行くの
This unstable lantern, just how far will it go?
あなた一切合切放り去ってもう
You've thrown everything away
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking around
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たら如何にもならないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholia
あたしをさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
So scoop me out now, take on me
はあ ちまちらおかしい法律ばかりで
Ha, with all these fussy, strange laws
食指がぴくりともしないわ
My appetite doesn't budge at all
実態のない感情放っといたって策略なんてありゃしないのに何故
Pointless emotions left alone, why is there no strategy?
ああもう懲り懲りよ あたしの喝となる気質も
Ah, I've had enough, my stern nature
じっと堪えて取り繕ってはととう臨界点
Patiently putting on a front until it reaches the critical point
年が年中リップサービス頽廃かましては駸々
All year round lip service, decadent bashing relentlessly
どんがらカシャンフィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
Feel girls are devils even with teary eyes
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
Now because of the music in my head, I can't hear your words at all
少しは真実なこと言って
Please say something truthful for once
回り出すターンテーブル
The turntable starts to spin
ねえ全部忘れさせてよ
Hey, let me forget everything
だけど一体全体如何して何故？
But why on earth, how, and why?
不安定なカンテラ消えない陰影
This unstable lantern and its lingering shadows
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもう
You're double-tongued and our stories don't match
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking around
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たら如何にもならないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholia
あたしをさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
So scoop me out now, take on me
はあ ちゃんちゃらおかしいハートばかりで
Ha, with all these ridiculous hearts
食指がぴくりともしないわ
My appetite doesn't budge at all
知ったいのない感情放っといたって策略なんてありゃしないのに何故
Pointless emotions left alone, why is there no strategy?
ああもう懲り懲りよ あたしのキャットナルピストも
Ah, I've had enough, my cat-like persistence too
じっとこらえて鳥居作ってはととう回転
Patiently holding back and building gates until it rotates
年が年中リップサービス頽廃かましては撃沈
All year round lip service, decadent bashing, totally sunk
どんがらカシャンフィールガールは涙の目にも似
Feel girls are devils even with teary eyes
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
Now because of the music in my head, I can't hear your words at all
おっしゃあまとものこと言って
Come on, say something sensible
終わりださっさとせいぜいせいぜい
It's over, hurry up, at best
忘れて捨ててよ
Forget it and throw it away
だいぶ一杯精一杯どうしてどうしてなって散々貼ってな
Quite full, doing my best, why, why, pasting it all over
不安定なカンテラ
This unstable lantern
消えないままで
Stays unquenched
あなたに個別撃破食い違ってもわお
Defeated individually, even if we clash, wow!
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking around
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たら如何にもならないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholia
私をさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
So scoop me out now, take on me
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking around, Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たら如何にもならないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholia
私をさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
So scoop me out now, take on me
冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
I'm not joking around, Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たら如何にもならないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing we can do
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカ化するだけ
Vague truths just turn into melancholia
私をさあ抉って今テイクオンミー
So scoop me out now, take on me
終わりださっさとせいぜいせいぜい
It's over, hurry up, at best
忘れて捨ててよ
Forget it and throw it away
だいぶ一杯精一杯どうしてどうしてなって散々貼ってな
Quite full, doing my best, why, why, pasting it all over
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
かふちゃん、いつもの挨拶とかありますか？
Kaf-chan, do you have your usual greeting?
こんばんは…こんばんは！
Good evening... Good evening!
かふちゃんが来てくれました！
Kaf-chan came to join us!
ありがとう、かふちゃん！
Thank you, Kaf-chan!
えーと、かふちゃん、すいちゃんそうなんですよ、呼んでくれるって。
Um, Kaf-chan, Suichan, that's right, she said she'd invite me.
あの、一緒に歌うのは、1年ぶりくらい？
And, singing together, it's been about a year?
そうだよね。
That's right, isn't it?
最後のが、Vフェス？うんうんうん。Vフェスが最後で。
The last one was V Fes? Yeah, V Fes was the last time.
あの、あれだったね、「幸子」歌いました。
Ah, that's right, we sang "Sachiko".
今日は、かふちゃんの曲「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」歌わせていただきました。歌わせてくれて…
Today, we got to sing Kaf-chan's song "Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous". Thank you for letting me sing it...
ふわふわな... ふわふわな
So fluffy... Such a fluffy
喋り方と 歌い方が特徴ですけれども
talking style and singing style are so distinctive,
普段は何をされている方なんですか?
what kind of work do you usually do?
普段は歌を歌っています。
I usually sing songs.
そうなんですよー!
That's right!
皆さんも知ってると思うんですけど、東京シャンテランデブー、これめちゃめちゃバズってますよね。
I'm sure everyone knows it, but "Tokyo Chante Rendez-vous" is totally buzzing right now.
めちゃくちゃバズっててすごいですね。
It's buzzing so much, it's amazing.
ね。
Right?
あ、それはやっぱ認知されてるバズってるのは?はい。
Ah, is that buzzing recognized widely? Yes.
周りからも すごいね。
Even from people around us, it's amazing.
東京シャンテランデブー、歌う上で、二人で振り付けも考えましたね。そうですね。
When singing "Tokyo Chante Rendez-vous", we even thought of the choreography together. That's right.
東京シャンテランデブー
Tokyo Chante Rendez-vous
ほぼでもね、カフちゃんが考えてくれた。
Almost, but Kaf-chan thought of it.
いやいやいやそんな
No, no, not at all.
イエスとか
Like "Yes" and stuff—
めちゃくちゃ可愛い。
So incredibly cute.
可愛い、カフちゃん!
So cute, Kaf-chan!
一緒にやってくれてすぐ、さすがだなと思って。
She did it with me right away, I thought "as expected of her".
そんなことないです。カフちゃん可愛いね。
Not at all. Kaf-chan is so cute.
あ、でもさ、おしゃべりするのはニッポン放送ラジオでちょっとね、おしゃべりしたので
Well, we chatted a bit on Nippon Broadcasting System radio, so
そうですね。
that's right.
おしゃべりするのはでも久しぶり感?
Is it been a while since we chatted?
そうだ。
That's right.
で、その時にね、すいちゃって呼んでくれるようになって
And at that time, you started calling me "Sui-chan".
すいちゃん、すいちゃん。
Sui-chan, Sui-chan.
あ、ありがとうございます。そのちょっといちゃいちゃを、あの、皆さんにお届けしたんですが
Ah, thank you very much. We delivered that little lovey-dovey moment to everyone,
カフちゃん、ちなみに何か宣伝することとかありますか?
Kafu-chan, by the way, do you have anything you'd like to promote?
あ、実はですね、サードアルバムの狂想が、えっと3月8日から配信リリースされているので
Ah, actually, my 3rd album "Kyoso" has been streaming since March 8th,
ぜひそちらをチェックしていただけたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
so I'd be happy if you could check it out. Thank you very much.
見どころは?
What's the highlight?
何ですか?全曲 聞いてほしい。
What is it? I want you to listen to every single song.
全曲ぜひ聞いてくださーい。
Please definitely listen to all of them.
お願いします。
Please do.
ということで、カフちゃんでした!
And with that, it was Kaf-chan!
ありがとうございました!
Thank you very much!
またねー!
See you again!
みちづれ 作詞・作曲:Ayase
[Song: Michizure / Lyrics & Music: Ayase]
人の世はいついつまでも 間違い探しばかり
This world is forever searching for mistakes,
遊び飽きたら終わりよ 鬼が出るか蛇が出るかと
it's all over once you tire of playing. Will an ogre or a snake appear next?
怖れて過ごすばかり さみぜめと一人泣くの
Living in perpetual fear, weeping bitterly all alone.
こんな旅路をゆくことが 人の条理とでも言うの
Would you really call taking such a journey human reasoning?
憂き身をやつせど うまく行かずに今夜もまた嘆く
Though I plunge myself into despair, nothing works out and I mourn again tonight.
だけどきっと これはパレードさ
But surely, this is a parade.
足を引っぱろうとも この滲み痛みと引き換えに
Even if they try to drag me down, in exchange for this seeping pain,
有余る喜びに 出会えるの
I'll find happiness in abundance.
これは愉快なパレードさ 私が生きた証ばかり撒くから
It's a delightful parade, scattering only the proof of my existence.
お気に召したなら共に行こう 道連れにしてあげるわ
If it's to your liking, let's go together. I'll take you along with me.
まやかしか化しか 知らない噂の一つや二つ
Is this trickery or deception? A rumor or two I wasn't aware of,
目を瞑ってあげる でも譲れない大事な想いは
I'll turn a blind eye. But these feelings that are dear to me,
歪むことなくちゃんと伝えたいの
I want to share them without distortion.
私は此処処よ 此処で生きているんだよ
I'm here, it's here that I live.
貴方と同じ心臓で刻む 鼓動に乗せて進むパレード
With a heart the same as yours, this parade travels to the beating of that heart.
どんな景色を見に行こう こんな私のことを
What sort of scenery shall we go looking for? Someone like me,
信じてくれるならどこまでもいける もう一人で泣いたりしないわ
if you believe in me, I can go anywhere. I won't cry alone anymore.
まやかしか化しか 知らない噂の一つや二つ
Is this trickery or deception? A rumor or two I wasn't aware of,
目を瞑ってあげる でも譲れない大事な想いは
I'll turn a blind eye. But these feelings that are dear to me,
歪むことなくちゃんと伝えたいの
I want to share them without distortion.
私は此処処よ 此処で生きているんだよ
I'm here, it's here that I live.
貴方と同じ心臓で刻む 鼓動に乗せて進むパレード
With a heart the same as yours, this parade travels to the beating of that heart.
どんな景色を見に行こう こんな私のことを
What sort of scenery shall we go looking for? Someone like me,
信じてくれるならどこまでもいける もう一人で泣いたりしないわ
if you believe in me, I can go anywhere. I won't cry alone anymore.
そしていつの日か私と 貴方の旅が終わり迎えた日には
And one day, when your journey with me meets its end,
抱え集めてきた荷物を もたげ放り投げて笑い合おう
the luggage we've collected, we'll throw them out and smile at each other.
そんな旅路を共に行こう
That's the kind of journey we should be on together.
人の世はいついつまでも 間違い探しばかり
This world is forever searching for mistakes,
遊び飽きたら終わりよ 鬼が出るか蛇が出るかと
it's all over once you tire of playing. Will an ogre or a snake appear next?
怖れて過ごすばかり さみぜめと一人泣くの
Living in perpetual fear, weeping bitterly all alone.
こんな旅路をゆくことが 人の条理とでも言うの
Would you really call taking such a journey human reasoning?
憂き身をやつせど うまく行かずに今夜もまた嘆く
Though I plunge myself into despair, nothing works out and I mourn again tonight.
だけどきっと これはパレードさ
But surely, this is a parade.
足を引っぱろうとも この滲み痛みと引き換えに
Even if they try to drag me down, in exchange for this seeping pain,
有余る喜びに 出会えるの
I'll find happiness in abundance.
これは愉快なパレードさ 私が生きた証ばかり撒くから
It's a delightful parade, scattering only the proof of my existence.
お気に召したなら共に行こう 道連れにしてあげるわ
If it's to your liking, let's go together. I'll take you along with me.
Please choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
HELL！ or HELL？ which do you (like！？)
HELL! or HELL? which do you (like!?)
HELL！ or HELL？ Which still？
HELL! or HELL? Which one do you want?
"It's too late to be sorry!!!"
HELL！ or HELL？ Which still？
HELL! or HELL? Which one do you want?
"It's too late to be sorry!!!"
僕の未来を
Seer these words into your mind
切り回した
until the very end
覚悟はあるか
Regret it now
Not afraid. (I'm ready.)
You shut up！！！
You shut up!!!
大切ーこのpainは (wow wow)
The most precious things (wow wow)
弱い残りよくまぼーぼー
I won't compromise even if I die
HELL！ or HELL？ どちらが欲しい？
HELL! or HELL? Which one do you want?
"Please help yourself!!!"
(You！ I'll never die！ I'll never die！)
(You! I'll never die! I'll never die!)
Hey！ Come on！！！
Hey! Come on!!!
(You！ I'll never die！ I'll never die！)
(You! I'll never die! I'll never die!)
この言葉最後まで
Seer these words into your mind
焼き付けておけ
until the very end
今に（今に）
Regret it now
Not afraid. (I'm ready.)
You shut up！！！
You shut up!!!
大切なものこそ (wow wow)
The most precious things (wow wow)
死んでも曲げはしないから
I won't compromise even if I die
（売られた喧嘩は） oi！！！ oi！！！
(The fight that was picked) oi!!! oi!!!
買いちゃうぞっ♪
I'll gladly buy it♪
図に乗れば堕ちていく (wow wow)
If you get full of yourself, you'll fall down (wow wow)
この世の定めを知れよ
Know the fate of this world
（因果応報） 仕方ない★ 報いををと今
(Retribution) It can't be helped ★ Take your punishment now
Please, choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
自分だけが良ければいいか？
Is it okay as long as you're the only one doing well?
…どのツラ下げて？
...With what face can you say that?
(You drive me nuts, yeah！！！)
(You drive me nuts, yeah!!!)
謝れば何でもOK？
If you apologize, is anything OK?
だったらポリスメンはいりませんyo！men！！！
Then policemen wouldn't be needed, yo! men!!!
HELL！ or HELL？ どちらも欲しい？
HELL! or HELL? Do you want both?
"Please help yourself!!!"
(You！ I'll never die！ I'll never die！)
(You! I'll never die! I'll never die!)
Hey！ Come on！！！
Hey! Come on!!!
(You！ I'll never die！ I'll never die！)
(You! I'll never die! I'll never die!)
馬鹿の相手は時間の無駄遣い
Dealing with idiots is a waste of time
ここで（ここで）サヨナラしま～す
Here and now, we say goodbye~
Not afraid. (I'm ready.)
Won't give in！！！
Won't give in!!!
心の声を聴け (wow wow)
Listen to the voice of your heart (wow wow)
怒りに飲まれんなよ絶対
Never let yourself be swallowed by anger
（相手の目線上） oi！！！ oi！！！
(Matching eyes with the opponent) oi!!! oi!!!
合わせんな！
Don't match them!
理不尽なオーダーなど (wow wow)
Unreasonable orders and such (wow wow)
従う必要なんかないさ
There's no need to obey them
（終わらせようか） この茶番★ 今すぐほら
(Shall we end it?) This farce ★ Right now, look
Please, choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
Hey！！！ 生きづらいのは仕方がない
Hey!!! It can't be helped that life is hard
まだまだ無理ゲーの世界みたい
It still seems like an impossible game world
Hey！！！ だけど死ねない諦めない
Hey!!! But I can't die, I won't give up
僕がやらなきゃ誰がやる？ ha！！！
If I don't do it, who will? ha!!!
HELL！ or (HELL？) HELL！ or (HELL？)
HELL! or (HELL?) HELL! or (HELL?)
HELL！ or (HELL？) Which do you like？
HELL! or (HELL?) Which do you like?
HELL！ or (HELL？) HELL！ or (HELL？)
HELL! or (HELL?) HELL! or (HELL?)
HELL！ or (HELL？) Which do you like？
HELL! or (HELL?) Which do you like?
まもなく時代は僕らのものへと
Soon the era will be ours
静けさの中にこそ真実があった
The truth existed only within the silence
瞳（閉じて）耳を澄ませ
Close your (eyes) and strain your ears
Not afraid. (I'm ready.)
You shut up！！！
You shut up!!!
大切なものこそ (wow wow)
The most precious things (wow wow)
死んでも曲げはしないから
I won't compromise even if I die
（売られた喧嘩は） oi！！！ oi！！！
(The fight that was picked) oi!!! oi!!!
買いちゃうぞっ♪
I'll gladly buy it♪
図に乗れば堕ちていく (wow wow)
If you get full of yourself, you'll fall down (wow wow)
この世の定めを知れよ
Know the fate of this world
（因果応報） 仕方ない★ 報いををと今
(Retribution) It can't be helped ★ Take your punishment now
Please, choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
HELL！ or HELL？ which do you (like！？)
HELL! or HELL? which do you (like!?)
Please, choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
HELL！ or HELL？ which do you (like！？)
HELL! or HELL? which do you (like!?)
僕らをみ～～んな 敵に回した覚悟はあるか
Are you prepared to make an enemy of all of us?
(It serves you right！！！)
(It serves you right!!!)
時代錯誤のbrain man
Anachronistic brain men
弱いワンちゃん良く鳴くワン♪ワン♪ワン♪
Weak puppies barking "Bow! Bow! Bow!"
HELL！ or HELL？ どちらが欲しい？
HELL! or HELL? Which one do you want?
"It's too late to be sorry！！"
"It's too late to be sorry!!!"
(You！ I'll never die！ I'll never die！)
(You! I'll never die! I'll never die!)
Hey！ Come on！！！
Hey! Come on!!!
(You！ I'll never die！ I'll never die！)
(You! I'll never die! I'll never die!)
この言葉最後まで焼き付けておけ
Seer these words into your mind until the very end
今に（今に）後悔せよ
Regret it now
Not afraid. (I'm ready.)
You shut up！！！
You shut up!!!
Please, choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
HELL！ or HELL？ which do you (like！？)
HELL! or HELL? which do you (like!?)
Please, choose！ HELL！ or HELL？
Please, choose! HELL! or HELL?
お願いします。
Thank you.
あ、うれしすぎる！ありがとうございます。聞いてくださって、自己紹介をお願いします。
Ah, I'm so happy! Thank you for listening, and please introduce yourselves.
はい、RAISE A SUILENベースボーカルのレイヤです。
Hi, I'm Raychell, bassist and vocalist for RAISE A SUILEN.
ギターのロックです。
I'm Rokka on guitar.
ドラムのマスキングだ。
And Masking on drums.
キーボードのパレオです。
I'm PAREO on keyboards.
プロデューサーそしてDJのチュチュよ。
And I'm CHU2, the producer and DJ.
よろしくお願いします！
Looking forward to working with you!
うわ、夢が叶った！ありがとうございます！
Wow, my dream came true! Thank you so much!
え、まず1曲目にレイヤさんと「道連れ」を歌っていただいたんですが、もうレイヤさんの歌声にすごくぴったりで、もうすごくうれしかったです、私の歌を歌っていただけて。
First, for the opening song, Raychell and I sang "Michizure." It suited your voice so well, and I was so happy you sang my song.
いや、私もすごくうれしかったです、本当に。どうでしたか？
I was so happy, too, really. How was it?
いや、すごく難しい楽曲なんですけれど、めちゃめちゃかっこいいですよね。
It's a really difficult song, but it's super cool, right?
そうなんです！すごいかっこよくて、あの、AYASAさんに曲卸していただいた楽曲で、
Exactly! It's so cool. Ayasa wrote it for us,
今日ね、レイヤさんと歌うということですごい緊張していたんですが、とっても完璧でした！
and since I was singing with Raychell today, I was so nervous, but it was totally perfect!
いやいやいや、私もすごく緊張したんですけれど、すごく楽しかったです。
No, no, I was super nervous too, but I had a lot of fun.
ありがとうございます！うれしい！
Thank you so much! I'm so happy!
そして、スイ星には私たちの「HELL! or HELL?」を歌ってもらったけど、感想を聞かせてもらえますか？
And Suisei sang our "HELL! or HELL?", could you share your thoughts on it?
あの、この曲もすごく難しかったですし、あと、なんか、すごい激しかったですよね。
Well, this song was also super difficult, and also, like, really intense.
もう、あと皆さんのパフォーマンスもすごかったので、もう感動しました、生でこんなふうに見られて。
And everyone's performance was amazing, so I was so moved seeing it live like this.
ありがとうございます、すごい光栄でした。
Thank you so much, it was such an honor.
そして私、あの、皆さんのライブにも実はいかせていただいたことがありまして、
And actually, I've had the chance to attend your live concerts before,
そのときもHELL! or HELL?すごい盛り上がりをさせていただきました。
and back then, "HELL! or HELL?" got everyone so hyped up too.
うれしい！
We're so glad!
サビでこうやりました。
I did this during the chorus.
激しいわね。
That's intense!
激しかった！
It really was!
スイ星さんはHELL! or HELL?でヘドバンをしてましたよね？
Suisei, you were headbanging during "HELL! or HELL?", weren't you?
はい！そうなんです！させていただきました！どうでしたか？
Yes! That's right! I did. How was it?
あ、なんか、すごい脳髄動が起こりそうな。
Ah, it felt like it might rattle your brain.
これいつも皆さんだって引きながらやられてるのがすごいなと思って、もう慣れっこなんですか？それは？そうですね。
I thought it was amazing how you all play while doing that, are you used to it by now? I guess so.
ライブワークです！
It's live work!
あれ？でもマスクさんさっきから随分と静かですが、もしかしてスイちゃんの可愛さに照れちゃってます？
Huh? But Masking, you've been pretty quiet since earlier. Could it be you're shy because of Sui-chan's cuteness?
え、ちょっとね、じゃあ時間もありますので、
Um, well, since we have some time,
ちょっと皆さんとツーショットを、いいですか？
can I take a two-shot with everyone?
カメラさん！
Cameraman!
ありがとうございます！やったあ！かわいい！かわいい！
Thank you! Yay! So cute! Cute!
はーと！うれしい！
Heart! I'm so happy!
チュチュさん！
Chu2-san!
本物よ！本物のよ！いつも歌聴いてるわ！
It's the real deal! The real deal! I always listen to your songs!
え、本当に！？オリジナル曲も！可愛い曲も！
Really?! Even your original songs! And cute songs too!
ファーストテイクも大好き！
I love your First Take as well!
本当に！？いいんですか？うれしい！
Really?! Is that okay? I'm so happy!
あんストッパブルもらっちゃった。あんストッパブル！ありがとうございます！
I got an "Unstoppable"! Thank you so much!
マスキングさん！
Masking!
おう。
Yeah.
かわいいな。褒めなさいよ。
So cute. Praise me!
マスキさんの顔！かわいい！
Mask-chan's face! Cute!
本当か？ありがとな。
Really? Thanks.
レイヤさん、じゃあ。ダブルピース！わあ、嬉しいです！レイヤさんもありがとう。
Raychell, then. Double peace! Wow, I'm so happy! Thank you too, Raychell.
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます。
No, thank you so much.
うわあ、もうこんな夢が叶い、私今日誕生日なんですよ、実は。
Wow, my dream came true like this. Today is actually my birthday, you know.
もう夢が叶い、最高！最高のプレゼントになりました。本当にありがとうございます。
My dream came true, it's amazing. It became the best present ever. Thank you so much.
次はね、もう私も、あの、皆さんのところに、おじゃましたいな、なんて。
Next time, I'd love to visit your side as well, or something.
バンドリさんよろしくおねがいします！ということで、以上スペシャルゲスト、RAISE A SUILENの皆さんでした！ありがとうございました！
Bang Dream, please take care of me! And with that, our special guests have been RAISE A SUILEN! Thank you very much!
祈る空に描く流星が
The shooting star drawn in the praying sky
ハピネスとミラクルを連れて
bringing happiness and miracles,
始まりを告げている
announcing the beginning.
KU-RU-KU-RU Cruller!
KU-RU-KU-RU Happy Dance!
空はつながってるよ
The sky is connected...
海もつながってるよ
The sea is connected too...
いつだって いつだって
Always, always,
心の中で 会えるから
we can meet inside our hearts.
さあ 目を閉じれば 現れる
Now, if you close your eyes, it appears—
僕らのステージが
our stage...
Let's dance with me 飛び込んだ世界で
Let's dance with me in this leaping world!
夢よまわれ… まわれ！
Dreams, spin around... and around!
どうなっちゃうんだ？
What's gonna happen?
楽しいなら 大丈夫さ
If it's fun, it's gonna be alright!
新しいやり方で Make you happy！
With a new way to make you happy!
おなじキモチだって
We share the same feelings,
分かっちゃう いつも分かっちゃう
we always understand each other.
君の想いが分かっちゃうんだ
I can understand your feelings too!
空へ向かって歌う
Singing toward the sky,
海に語りかけてる (今もね)
speaking to the sea (even now).
いつだって いつだって
Always, always,
耳をすませば 聞こえるよ
if you listen closely, you can hear it.
そう 目を開いても 終わらない
Yes, even if you open your eyes, it won't end—
僕らのステージは
our stage is
Endless Passion
重なった世界で 夢よまわれ… まわれ！
In this overlapping world, dreams spin around... and around!
どうなっちゃいたい？
What do you want to become?
ずっとずっと 遊んでたい
I want to keep playing forever and ever.
遠くても 君の声で Make me happy！
Even from afar, with your voice, make me happy!
おなじキモチ だよね
It's the same feeling, right?
君の願いも 分かっちゃうんだ
I can understand your wishes too!
ツナガリタイ いつだって
I want to connect, always.
君へとつながる 場所がある
There's a place that connects me to you.
心から 心へと つながる 音は消えないよ
The sound connecting heart to heart will never disappear.
信じているんだ
I believe in it.
君には伝わると 大好きが伝わると (大好き！)
It will reach you, my deep love will reach you! (Love you!)
これだけは変わらない
This alone will never change—
To make you happy！
to make you happy!
出逢えたことが Lucky
Meeting you is lucky,
君が笑えば Happy
when you smile, it's happy.
Ah 単純だね 君が大好きだよ！
Ah, it's so simple, I love you so much!
どうなっちゃいたい？
What do you want to become?
ずっとずっと 遊んでたい
I want to keep playing forever and ever.
遠くても 君の声で Make me happy！
Even from afar, with your voice, make me happy!
おなじキモチ だよね
It's the same feeling, right?
キノウの願いも 分かっちゃうんだ
I can understand yesterday's wishes too!
つながりたい いつだって
I want to connect, always.
君へとつながる 場所がある
There's a place that connects me to you.
心から 心へと つながる お手上げないよ
The sound connecting heart to heart won't stop!
信じているんだ 君には伝わると
I believe it will reach you.
大好きが伝わると (大好き！)
My love will reach you! (I love you!)
許せ 一秒 かけたら様が
If you give me just one second,
夢の道はずっとネット
the road of dreams is always connected.
視線 誰にも 譲れない
I won't yield my gaze to anyone!
Please Get On Me
きっと始まるときが来たんだ
Surely, the time to begin has come!
これだけは変わらない
This alone will never change—
To Make You Happy！
to make you happy!
出逢えたことが Lucky
Meeting you is lucky,
君が笑えば Happy
when you smile, it's happy.
Ah 単純だね 君が大好きだよ！
Ah, it's so simple, I love you so much!
大好きだよ！
I love you so much!
どうなっちゃいたい？
What do you want to become?
ずっとずっと 遊んでたい
I want to keep playing forever and ever.
遠くても 君の声で Make me happy！
Even from afar, with your voice, make me happy!
おなじキモチ だよね
It's the same feeling, right?
キノウの願いも 分かっちゃうんだ
I can understand yesterday's wishes too!
ずっとずっと 遊んでたい
I want to keep playing forever and ever.
遠くても 君の声で Make you happy！
Even from afar, with your voice, make you happy!
おなじキモチ だよね
It's the same feeling, right?
楽しいなら 大丈夫さ
If it's fun, it's gonna be alright!
新しいやり方で Make you happy！
With a new way to make you happy!
おなじキモチ だよね
It's the same feeling, right?
キノウの願いも 分かっちゃうんだ
I can understand yesterday's wishes too!
いつだって つながる場所がある
Always, there is a place to connect.
心から 心へと つながるんだ
Connecting from heart to heart.
信じているんだ 君には伝わると
I believe it will reach you.
大好きが伝わると
My love will reach you!
KU-RU-KU-RU Happy Dance!
始まった fantastic time
A fantastic time begins
ゴールはスポットライト
The goal is the spotlight
I am the ヒロイン
I am the heroine
迎えに来て Freak it on me
Come pick me up, Freak it on me
きっと始まる fantastic time
Surely, a fantastic time begins
みんな準備はいいですか？
Everyone, are you ready?
バーニー うなづいて
Burning, nod along,
隠炎も Heat up でしょ
Even shadows heat up, right?
どうしよう、どうしよう
What should I do, what should I do?
明るく浮き
Brightly floating,
レッツゴー さあ、太陽
Let's go, now, the sun
燃えて最高潮ねぇ
Burning to the climax, hey!
負けないれな 鼓動もハートも
I won't lose, my heartbeat and heart
かけひきは ののげ
The bargaining is non-stop
開いたなら
If it opens,
走れ明日のほうへ
Run toward tomorrow!
許せ一秒 かけたらサヨナカズ
Forgive me, if I spend a second, goodbye
夢の道は ストリート
The road of dreams is a street
自然誰にも譲れない
I won't yield to anyone
Freak it on me
きっと湧き出す fantastic time
Surely welling up, a fantastic time
ゴールはスポットライト
The goal is the spotlight
I am the ヒロイン
I am the heroine
迎えに来て Freak it on me
Come pick me up, Freak it on me
きっと湧き出す fantastic time
Surely welling up, a fantastic time
絶対 最上 つかみたい Feeling
Definitely want to grasp the supreme feeling
全身 全霊 めくるめく Get hot
With all my body and soul, a dazzling get hot
テンション 高揚 星屑揺れ
Tension rising, stardust swaying
今宵 Together 一紹介
Tonight, together for an introduction
迎えるとき 遠慮はいらない
When welcoming, no hesitation is needed
せめぎ合い Oh oh Spark
A tug of war, oh oh, spark
アセットプライド 散れど運命
Asset pride, though scattered, destiny
連れて明日のほうへ
Take me toward tomorrow
挑む世界は 魅惑のサヴァイバー
The world I challenge is a fascinating survivor
天井知らずの ボルステージ
A stage with no ceiling in sight
ホテル季節 モノヌシで
Hotel seasons, as the owner
震えさせて Exciting time
Make it tremble, exciting time
ゴールはスポットライト
The goal is the spotlight
I am the ヒロイン
I am the heroine
迎えに来て Freak it on me
Come pick me up, Freak it on me
きっと湧き出す fantastic time
Surely welling up, a fantastic time
間違い探せだせたら Winner
If you can find the mistakes, you're a winner
熱くなれば 一歩で Change and Happy
If we get hot, change and happy in one step
眩しすぎる今日を 踊るように手にしよう
Let's take today, too dazzling, into our hands as if dancing
ビートは止まらない
The beat won't stop
想うままに 身を預けて
Entrust your body as you feel
灼熱へ Go Go Warp
To the scorching heat, go, go, warp
踊るリズム 打ち鳴らして
Ringing out the dancing rhythm
走れ明日のほうへ
Run toward tomorrow
許せ一秒 かけたらサヨナカズ
Forgive me, if I spend a second, goodbye
夢の道は ストリート
The road of dreams is a street
誰にも譲れない Freak it on me
I won't yield to anyone, Freak it on me
きっと始まる fantastic time
Surely, a fantastic time begins
ゴールはスポットライト
The goal is the spotlight
I am the ヒロイン
I am the heroine
迎えに来て Freak it on me
Come pick me up, Freak it on me
きっと始まる fantastic time
Surely, a fantastic time begins
Starry jet
星屑をまとわせたい
I want to clothe you in stardust
Starry jet
眩しさに目を細めて
Squinting at the dazzling light
止んだクラクション
The stopped claxon
ざわめきまでのヒステリックな間柄
A hysterical relationship up to the murmur
喧騒を脱いで
Throwing off the hustle and bustle
きらめき取り戻す
Regaining the sparkle
Hey! Join us!
夜空をかける ストリーム
A stream running through the night sky
Join us!
乗り遅れないでね
Don't miss it, okay?
満差点 心地良さ競り合いの音楽
Resounding music competing for comfort
ときに散りばめて 神秘に輝きで満たすよ
Scattering time, filling with mysterious radiance
成功 今やステージに立とうよ
Success, now let's stand on stage
始まり眠れぬ街で 君とステージになる
In a city where sleep eludes the beginning, with you, it becomes a stage
止まったクラクション さっきまでの
With the horns stopped, the city
ヒステリックな街が
that was hysterical until just now
喧騒を脱いで キラメキ取り戻す
sheds its noise and regains its sparkle.
hey! join us! we are starry starry jet!
夜空を駆け抜ける ストリーム
A stream racing across the night sky.
join us! we are party party jet!
乗り遅れないでね
Don't miss out on it.
midnight tunes ココチイイ 選びすぐりの 音楽たちを
Midnight tunes, hand-picked comfortable music
散りばめて ジュエリー 輝きで 満たすよ
scattered around, filling with jewelry shine.
take off
Take-off!
今夜 流れ星になろうよ party mind 眠れぬ街で
Tonight let's become shooting stars with a party mind in the sleepless city,
キミと 流れ星になるんだ 盛り上がろう
becoming shooting stars with you, let's get hyped!
take you higher 手を取って
Take you higher, holding hands,
パーティーは 始まったばかり
the party has only just begun.
take you higher 連れてくよ
Take you higher, I'll take you there,
さあ、一緒に flight!!
Now, let's fly together!
そっと 閉じて 瞳の奥 光を追いかける
Gently closing our eyes, chasing the light deep within,
消えてしまう前に 覚えておきたくて
wanting to remember it before it fades away.
ねえ、朝に還るなんて 謎 ネガティブなんだ ナンデ？
Hey, why are we so negatively puzzled about returning to morning?
って、自問自答ループ くらい そりゃ 上級者グループ
That kind of self-questioning loop is for the advanced group!
ow! 一旦 フリーズ フリーズ どなた様も アテンション・プリーズ
Ow! Once freeze, freeze, attention please to everyone,
明日にとっておきの思い出を
making tomorrow's memories extra special.
midnight pain 綺麗だね キミの生き方が綺麗なんだ
Midnight pain, how beautiful your way of living is,
それぞれが ジュエリー 輝きで 満ちてる
each and every one of us filled with jewelry's brilliance.
今夜 流れ星になろうよ キミと 流れ星になるんだ ah
Tonight let's become shooting stars, becoming shooting stars with you, ah.
キラリ
Sparkling,
ねえ、踊る星の一粒さえ この街に欠かせないなら
Hey, if even a single dancing star is indispensable to this city,
そんな 今日が 本懐と 今 言えるかも
we might just be able to say today is our ultimate fulfillment.
どこまでも starry starry jet
To the ends of the earth, starry starry jet,
このまま 夜が明けるまで
until the night breaks just like this.
トクベツな party party jet
A special party party jet,
まだ 終われない
it's not over yet.
盛り上がれ starry starry jet
Get hyped, starry starry jet,
朝が 来たって 忘れ ない
even when morning comes, we won't forget.
最高 の party party jet
The greatest party party jet,
さあ、一緒に flight!!
Now, let's fly together!
パン パカ パパン ハイ！
Pa-n pa-ka pa-pa-n, hey!
パパン パカ ハイ！
Pa-pa-n pa-ka, hey!
パパン パパン パパン ハイ！
Pa-pa-n pa-pa-n pa-pa-n, hey!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今宵 水晶になるのよ
Tonight we'll become crystal,
キミと 水晶になるんだ ah
becoming crystal with you, ah.
きらり 踊る 星の 一粒さえ
Sparkling, even a single dancing star,
君の街に 欠かせないなら
if it's indispensable to your town,
そんな 今日が 本懐と 今 言えるかも
we might just be able to say today is our ultimate fulfillment.
どこまでも starry starry jet
To the ends of the earth, starry starry jet,
このまま 夜が明けるまで
until the night breaks just like this.
トクベツな party party jet
A special party party jet,
まだ 終われない
it's not over yet.
盛り上がれ starry starry jet
Get hyped, starry starry jet,
朝が 来たって 忘れ ない
even when morning comes, we won't forget.
最高 の party party jet
The greatest party party jet,
さあ、一緒に flight!!
Now, let's fly together!
パン パカ パパン ハイ！
Pa-n pa-ka pa-pa-n, hey!
パパン パカ ハイ！
Pa-pa-n pa-ka, hey!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
皆様、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so, so much!
ちょっと、ゼハゼハしているんですけれども、
I'm a little out of breath right now, but,
えー、ここからは告知タイムになります！
um, from here on is our announcement time!
本日告知がたくさんありますが、駆け足でやっていきたいと思います！もう9時ですので、まずは、こちら！
There are lots of announcements today, but I want to rush through them! It's already 9 o'clock, so first up is this!
本日出演したRoseliaさんが登場しているバンドリ！ ガールズバンドパーティ！は、
Bandori! Girls Band Party! featuring Roselia who performed today
3月16日に超大型アップデートを実施しました！超大型アップデートにより3Dライブモードが実装され、自分の好きなバンド編成で好きな衣装を着せてリズムゲームが楽しめるそうです！ぜひ遊んでみてください！
has implemented a massive update on March 16th! With this massive update, 3D live mode has been implemented, and you can enjoy rhythm games with your favorite band composition and outfits! Please play it!
え、お次、お次！
Um, next, next!
え、レギュラー化が発表されていたNHKラジオVRCですが、この度公式Twitterができました！初回放送は4月9日日曜日22時40分からです！
Um, NHK Radio VR, which was announced to become a regular show, now has an official Twitter! The first broadcast is on Sunday, April 9th at 22:40!
次は新情報ですよー！行きます、どん！
Next is new info! Here we go, boom!
なんとこの度、ハウス食品さん、イトーヨーカドーさんとコラボさせていただきました！オリジナルレトルトカレー【星街家のカレー】の発売が決定しました！何度も試食を作っていただきまして、私もしっかりと監修を重ねて、名の通り、すいちゃんの「実家」の味にできる限り近づけた味わいとなっております。
Amazingly, this time we've collaborated with House Foods and Ito-Yokado! The release of our original retort curry, "Hoshimachi Family Curry," has been decided! After making countless tasting samples and thoroughly supervising it myself, it's flavored to be as close as possible to Su-chan's "home" taste as promised.
もちろん、具の野菜はジャガイモとタマネギだけになってますよ！こちらは4月10日からイトーヨーカドーネット通販で予約が開始予定となります！お楽しみに！
Of course, the vegetable ingredients are only potatoes and onions! Reservations for this will start on Ito-Yokado's online shop from April 10th! Look forward to it!
そして、お次！
And, next!
え、この度専門学校HALさんの2023年度CMソングの歌唱を担当...
I am in charge of singing the 2023 CM song for vocational school HAL...
ることになりました！曲を誰が作ったかは明日発表されるみたいです。
It's been decided! The creator of the song will be announced tomorrow.
CMは24日金曜日から春のホームページで見れますので
The commercial will be available on Haru's homepage starting Friday the 24th,
ぜひチェックしてください！
so please check it out!
そして、このCMはなんとテレビでも流れるんです。見た人はぜひツイートで教えてくださーい！
And this commercial will actually broadcast on television! If you see it, please let us know on Twitter!
ふう…ひと息ついて、では次のVTRいきますよ！どん！
Whew... Let's take a breath, and now for the next VTR! Here we go, boom!
遊び飽きたら終わりよ
Once you tire of playing, it's over.
鬼が出るか蛇が出るかと
Wondering if an ogre or a snake will appear,
だけどきっと
But surely,
これはパレードさ
this is a parade.
どんな景色を見に行こう
What kind of scenery shall we go see?
もう一人で泣いたりしないわ
I won't cry alone anymore.
星が揺らいて 夢を見ている
The stars are swaying, having a dream.
焦がれたその音が待っているの
The sound I yearned for is waiting for me.
キラめくカラー 秘めている日々に
In days hiding sparkling colors,
伝えるこのメロディ
I convey this melody.
窓から覗いた 雨の降る街並みを
Looking out the window at the rainy cityscape,
弾ける音だから ポケットに詰め込んで Let's dance now
stuff it into your pocket and let's dance now.
君の好きな （ちょっとcoolでpopなparty song）
Your favorite (A little cool and pop party song)
キラーチューンのステップに乗せて
Riding on the steps of a killer tune,
魔法のような （もっとvivid, passion, shiny ray）
Like magic (More vivid, passion, shiny ray)
ライトが私を照らしている
the lights are shining on me.
星を紡いで 夢を描くよ
Spinning stars, I'll draw a dream.
焦がれたその声が呼んでいるの
The voice I yearned for is calling me.
キラめくカラー まとった君に 届けるこのメロディ
To you, draped in sparkling colors, I deliver this melody.
このままじゃね終われない （終わらない）
I can't end like this (Won't end)
SpecialなStage 踊り明かすの （明かそう）
Dancing the night away on a special stage (Let's dance)
このままじっとしてられない （そうさせない）
I can't stay still like this (Won't let you)
走り出そうよ 明日は晴れるから
Let's start running because tomorrow will be sunny.
まだ目が覚めない カーテンを開けても 憂鬱そうだと コメントが流れたら Let's show now
Even if I open the curtains, still not fully awake...
いつも着てた （ちょっとtrend baseなgirly style）
Always wearing (A little trend base girly style)
ショーウィンドウの服着替えて
Changing clothes in the storefront window,
魔法のような （もっとcoolでpopなparty time）
Like magic (More vivid, passion, shiny ray)
ドレスがふわりってひるがえる
my dress flutters softly.
満天の星空にほら 浮かべてみて明日のビジョン
In the starry sky, look, picture tomorrow's vision.
そこで見える そこで見えるなら もっと飛べるよ
If you can see it there, you can fly higher.
満開の笑顔ならほら 歌ってみせてこのドキドキ
If it's a full bloom smile, look, sing this excitement.
そこ で 会 え る そこ で 会 え る か ら だ っ て き っ と 世 界 は 変 わ る か ら ！
Because we can meet there, for sure, the world will change!
明日は晴れるから
Because tomorrow will be sunny,
星を紡いで 夢を描くよ
spinning stars, I'll draw a dream.
星が揺らいて 夢を見ている
The stars are swaying, having a dream.
焦がれたその音が待っているの
The sound I yearned for is waiting for me.
キラめくカラー 秘めている日々に 伝えるこのメロディ
In days hiding sparkling colors, I convey this melody.
このままじゃね終われない （終わらない）
I can't end like this (Won't end)
SpecialなStage 踊り明かすの （明かそう）
Dancing the night away on a special stage (Let's dance)
このままじっとしてられない （そうさせない）
I can't stay still like this (Won't let you)
走り出そうよ 世界は変わるから
Let's start running because the world will change.
(la, la la la la la la la la)
(la la la la la)
明日は晴れるから
Because tomorrow will be sunny,
明日も会えるから！
because we can meet tomorrow too!
見える そこで見えるなら
Can you see it? If you can see it there,
もっと飛べるよ
you can fly even higher!
真っ赤な笑顔なら ほら 歌ってみて
If you have a bright red smile, hey, try singing along!
このときめき
This excitement
そこであえる
We can meet there,
そこであえるから
because we can meet there,
だってきっと 世界は変わるから
because surely, the world will change!
星を紡いで 夢を描くよ
Spinning stars, I'll paint a dream
焦がれたその声が呼んでいるの
The voice I longed for is calling out
煌めくカラー まとった君に 届けるこのメロディ
Delivering this melody to you, wrapped in glittering colors
このままじゃね 終わらない
It won't end just like this,
SpecialなStage 踊り明かすの
dancing the night away on a special stage!
走り出そうよ 世界は変わるから
Let's start running, because the world will change!
明日は晴れるから
Because tomorrow will be clear and sunny!
明日も会えるから！
Because I'll be able to see you tomorrow too!
星街すいせい 誕生日＆活動5周年記念グッズ今年も販売します！
Hoshimachi Suisei's Birthday & 5th Anniversary goods are on sale!
このあとすぐ販売開始です！
Sales will begin right after this!
ひなた先生描き下ろしのキャンバスアート
Canvas Art illustrated by Hinata-sensei,
れいか先生描き下ろしのランダムラバーキーホルダー
Random Rubber Keychain illustrated by Reika-sensei,
すいちゃんクッション
the Suichan Cushion,
普段使いもできるCOMETクリアショルダーバッグ
and the COMET Clear Shoulder Bag for everyday use!
フルセット販売もあります
Full set sales are also available.
フルセットを購入してくださった方にはポストカードがついてきます！
Those who purchase the full set will receive a postcard!
ぜひ買ってください！
Please be sure to buy them!
Shining Memory Hoshimachi Suisei 5th Anniversary start 2023.03.22
[Shining Memory - Hoshimachi Suisei 5th Anniversary (Starts March 22, 2023)]